



Key skills

- Sales
- International Sales
- Business Development
- Key Account Management
- International Business Development
- Client Relationship Management
- Enterprise Sales
- Revenue Generation
- Client Engagement
- Business Strategist
- Business Development Manager



Personal Information

City Gurugram

Country INDIA



Languages

- HINDI
- ENGLISH

Sujit Kumar Singh

AM-Business Development



8 Years 5 Months



-91) 9711301883



oin2suiit786@vahoo.i



Profile Summary

With around 8 years of rich experience in the IT sector, I have developed a strong track record in project execution, business development, and client relationship management. My expertise lies in the latest technologies like AI, ML, AR/VR, Blockchain, Ecommerce, SAAS, and Mobile Application Development. I have successfully led business and development teams, providing innovative solutions to global clientele and achieving sales of more than \$2.5 Lakhs annually.

I am well-versed in international and domestic client interactions, requirement gathering, analysis, documentation, cost estimations, negotiation, and resource analysis. My comprehensive knowledge of different verticals like BFSI, Educational domain, Hospitality, Retailing, Social Network, E-commerce, Service On Deman, Real Estate, B2B solutions, etc., has helped me in driving positive change, cohesive, comprehensive business approaches, and enhancing profitability.



Education

MBA/PGDM, 2015

Uttar Pradesh Technical University (UPTU)

B.Tech/B.E., 2012

Uttar Pradesh Technical University (UPTU)



Work Experience

Mar 2024 - Sep 2024

AM-Business Development

Valuecoders

I worked here as an Inbound Assistant Manager in Business Development and responsible for client handling and acquisitions for Web & Mobile App development on varoius technologies like PHP, Javascript, Golang, ROR, Python, React Native, Flutter, Swift-3 etc, SAAS based custom software development, Cloud Computing and Migration, Dashboard creation for the data coming from various tools like Power BI, Tableau, Google Analytics etc, AI & ML integration, providing various resources on technologies like React, Angular, Data Analytics, Python, Servicenow, Adobe Experience Manager and other cutting edge tecgnologies.

I am into client engagement, requirement gathering, quotation sharing, preparing Proposals and other project finalization documents, negotiations, co-ordinate with the technical pre-sales team to get the technical efforts required based on the shared requirement details by the client and share the needful details and documents (Proposals, agreements, Contracts etc.) in order to close the project and getting it onboard

I was also responsible to introduce the technical team who are going to work on the project and key accounts management for futuristic opportunities.

Aug 2021 - Dec 2023

Business Strategist

Think Design Collaborative Pvt. Ltd.

Responsible for generating revenue for the organisation through adding new clients. In order to do this, I consult with the inbound leads and entertain them to understand their requirement to facilitate the best possible solution. Co-ordinate with the design team for preparing fully fledged Business Proposals, Contracts and other required documents for the closure of projects. Responsible for account management to track the timely milestone payments of key client and maintain a relationship for further opportunities.

Jan 2019 - Feb 2021

Inside sales and Customer Relationship Manager

QuyTech

Dealt with many AR/VR, AI/ML, Gaming and Mobile Application development related projects and achieved 100% of target allocated in terms of New Business Closure as well as Payment Collection. Responsible for effectively communicating with the stakeholders and drafting the solution requirement document (SRD). Communicate with the development team to ensure the gathered requirements are understandable for their development tasks. Followed agile concepts effectively and implemented all the events of scrum to follow every two weeks release lifecycles.

Jul 2017 - May 2018

Associate Consultant Business Development

Oodles Technologies

Managed high-performance sales and marketing teams of 5 team members and provide them the knowledge of client communication, requirement gathering which results in the revenue generation for the company in niche technologies like Blockchain, Video Streaming, Al, CRM development related work. Responsible for effectively communicating the new strategic objectives of the company with senior management to drive the business forward. Initiate the Bidding Procedures by creating profiles on Upwork, PPH, GURU and generate revenue from there as well. Communicate with senior management on the current business strategy and what elements of that plan should be shared with employees to help make them more efficient in their daily work activities. Responsible for analyzing the output coming from the team members and also motivate them for better performance by providing them incentives and team parties on the basis of closures.

Mar 2015 - Jun 2017

Business Development Executive

Creative Squadz

213 Days

Vida World

The overall website for Vida E-Bikes has been designed and developed form scratch

1640 Days

Lavena Cafe Food Ordering App

Food ordering app for single restaurent with multiple resources. POS integration is also there. Cross-platform App on React Native with Backend on Node.js

122 Days

AR Virtual Tryon Jewellery

User can virtually try the rings and place the purchase order. It is a markerless solution.

184 Days

AR App for an Event

We have developed this application for experiencing an AR effect in an event while pointing the camera to the stage.

1976 Days

E-Learning Application

We have integrated the Application with client's LMS and we have developed the app for providing the online learning to the interested candidates

2006 Days

Safehouse Health Appointment App

It is an application for online consultation with the doctors for getting the desies resolved without going at any clinic.

184 Days

SOS Application

It is a SOS application developed for a security company located in Malaysia with the name of Terra EMS.

2096 Days

Mindful Happiness

It is a yoga and meditation application similar to Headspace.